<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metrics on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/metrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Metrics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:08:49 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/metrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Metrics for Classification Problems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ml_concepts/classification_metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:08:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ml_concepts/classification_metrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/20230920_classification_metrics/classification_metrics.gif&#34; alt=&#34;classification metrics&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification-problems&#34;&gt;Classification Problems&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Supervised Machine Learning projects can be divided into &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_analysis&#34;&gt;regression&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification&#34;&gt;classification&lt;/a&gt; problems. In regression problems, we predict a continuous variable (e.g. temperature), while in classification, we classify the data into discrete classes (e.g. classify cat and dog images). A subset of classification problems is the so-called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_classification&#34;&gt;binary classification&lt;/a&gt;, where only two classes are considered. An example of this is classifying e-mails as spam and no-spam or cat images versus dog images. When we consider more than two classes, we speak of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiclass_classification&#34;&gt;multi-class classification&lt;/a&gt;. An example of this is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MNIST_database&#34;&gt;MNIST&lt;/a&gt; dataset, where images of handwritten digits are classified, i.e. we have 10 different classes. Depending on the problem we consider, we need different metrics to evaluate our Machine Learning model. Within each of these two types of Machine Learning problems, we have to choose which of the metrics fits our needs best. This post will give an overview of the most common metrics for &lt;strong&gt;binary classification&lt;/strong&gt; problems, what they mean, and when to use them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metrics for Regression Problems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ml_concepts/regression_metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 21:24:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ml_concepts/regression_metrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/20231001_regression_metrics/regression_metrics.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;regression metrics&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;regression-problems&#34;&gt;Regression Problems&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_analysis&#34;&gt;Regression&lt;/a&gt; problems in Machine Learning are a type of supervised learning problem, where a continuous numerical variable is predicted, such as, for example, the age of a person or the price of a product. A special type is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/classical_ml/linear_regression/&#34; title=&#34;Linear Regression&#34;&gt;Linear Regression&lt;/a&gt;, where a linear relationship between two (&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/classical_ml/linear_regression/#slr&#34; title=&#34;Linear Regression&#34;&gt;Simple Linear Regression&lt;/a&gt; or more (&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/classical_ml/linear_regression/#mlr&#34; title=&#34;Linear Regression&#34;&gt;Multiple Linear Regression&lt;/a&gt;) is analyzed. The example plots in this article will be illustrated with a simple linear regression. However the metrics introduced here are common metrics for all types of regression problems, including multiple linear regression and non-linear regression. The simple linear regression is only chosen for illustration purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
