<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificial Intelligence on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/artificial-intelligence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artificial Intelligence on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 22:49:06 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Backpropagation - Step by Step</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ml_concepts/backpropagation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 22:49:06 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ml_concepts/backpropagation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Example: 1 Neuron Example: 2 Neurons Example: Small Network General Formulation Summary Appendix Derivative of the Sigmoid Function The Sigmoid Function is defined as&#xA;$$\sigma(x) = \frac{1}{1 + e^{-1}}$$&#xA;The derivative is then&#xA;$$\sigma\prime(x)$$&#xA;If this blog is useful for you, I&amp;rsquo;m thankful for your support! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bias and Variance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ml_concepts/bias_variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 09:39:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ml_concepts/bias_variance/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In Machine Learning different error sources exist. Some errors cannot be avoided, for example, due to unknown variables in the system analyzed. These errors are called irreducible errors. On the other hand, reducible errors, are errors that can be reduced to improve the model&amp;rsquo;s skill. Bias and Variance are two of the latter. They are concepts used in supervised Machine Learning to evaluate the model&amp;rsquo;s output compared to the true values.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Deep Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/deep_learning/intro_dl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 21:44:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/deep_learning/intro_dl/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will learn what Deep Learning is and understand the difference to AI and Machine Learning. Often these three terms are used interchangeable. They are however not the same. The following diagram illustrates how they are related.&#xA;Relation of Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning and Deep Learning.&#xA;Artificial Intelligence. There are different definitions of Artificial Intelligence, but in general, they involve computers performing tasks that are usually associated with humans or other intelligent living systems.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
